<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Board of Directors | Center of Complex Interventions</title>
	<atom:link href="https://centerofci.org/department/board-of-directors/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://centerofci.org/</link>
	<description>Helping Communities Translate Science Into Action</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:36:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://centerofci.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cropped-CCI-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Board of Directors | Center of Complex Interventions</title>
	<link>https://centerofci.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Colin Raney</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/colin-raney/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Colin Raney is the Chief Marketing Officer of PillPack and Director of Marketing at Amazon Pharmacy. Prior to PillPack, Colin served as the CMO of 3D-printing company Formlabs and as Managing Director at IDEO, the world-renowned design and innovation firm. He is an advisor to multiple startups, has written for The Harvard Business Review and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Colin Raney is the Chief Marketing Officer of PillPack and Director of Marketing at Amazon Pharmacy. Prior to PillPack, Colin served as the CMO of 3D-printing company Formlabs and as Managing Director at IDEO, the world-renowned design and innovation firm. He is an advisor to multiple startups, has written for The Harvard Business Review and Fast Company.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michelle Kydd Lee</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/michelle-kydd-lee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Michelle Kydd Lee is a Board Member and Chief Innovation Officer at Creative Artists Agency, where she provides strategic leadership that builds upon the agency&#8217;s renowned culture of collaboration and client service, and crafts state-of-the-art approaches to empower and develop employees. Kydd Lee has been a driving force for CAA&#8217;s diversity and inclusion initiatives, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Michelle Kydd Lee is a Board Member and Chief Innovation Officer at Creative Artists Agency, where she provides strategic leadership that builds upon the agency&#8217;s renowned culture of collaboration and client service, and crafts state-of-the-art approaches to empower and develop employees. Kydd Lee has been a driving force for CAA&#8217;s diversity and inclusion initiatives, and is a founding member of TIME&#8217;S UP. In 1995, she founded the CAA Foundation to create positive social change. Kydd Lee, who directed the CAA Foundation until 2015, serves as a consultant to clients, executives, and corporations on their philanthropic and social impact initiatives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reid Hoffman</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/reid-hoffman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 12:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Co-Founder of LinkedIn Partner at Greylock An accomplished entrepreneur, executive, and investor, Reid Hoffman has played an integral role in building many of today’s leading consumer technology businesses. In 2003 he co-founded LinkedIn, the world’s largest professional networking service. In 2009 he joined Greylock. He currently serves on the boards of Apollo, Aurora, Coda, Convoy, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Co-Founder of LinkedIn</p>



<p>Partner at Greylock</p>



<p>An accomplished entrepreneur, executive, and investor, Reid Hoffman has played an integral role in building many of today’s leading consumer technology businesses. In 2003 he co-founded LinkedIn, the world’s largest professional networking service. In 2009 he joined Greylock. He currently serves on the boards of Apollo, Aurora, Coda, Convoy, Entrepreneur First, Microsoft, Nauto, Neeva, Xapo, and a few early stage companies still in stealth. In addition, he serves on a number of not-for-profit boards, including Kiva, Endeavor, CZI Biohub, New America, Berggruen Institute, Opportunity@Work, the Stanford Institute for Human-Centered AI, and the MacArthur Foundation’s Lever for Change. He is the host of Masters of Scale, an original podcast series and the first American media program to commit to a 50-50 gender balance for featured guests. He is the co-author of three best-selling books:&nbsp;<em>The Start-Up of You</em>,&nbsp;<em>The Alliance</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Blitzscaling</em>. He is an Aspen Institute Crown Fellow, a Marshall Scholar at Oxford, and a graduate of Stanford University.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
