<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Core Team | Center of Complex Interventions</title>
	<atom:link href="https://centerofci.org/department/team/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://centerofci.org/</link>
	<description>Helping Communities Translate Science Into Action</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:28:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://centerofci.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cropped-CCI-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Core Team | Center of Complex Interventions</title>
	<link>https://centerofci.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Samantha Bates</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/samantha-bates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Samantha Bates is the Executive Director of CCI where she sets the strategic vision for the organization, runs day-to-day operations, and works closely with the CCI research team on various research projects. Before CCI, Sam was the Director of Administration at YarnLabs Inc, a fiscal sponsor for non-profits. She also previously managed research at MIT [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Samantha Bates is the Executive Director of CCI where she sets the strategic vision for the organization, runs day-to-day operations, and works closely with the CCI research team on various research projects. Before CCI, Sam was the Director of Administration at YarnLabs Inc, a fiscal sponsor for non-profits. She also previously managed research at MIT and worked as a researcher at Harvard Law School and the Berkman Klein Center for Internet &amp; Society. Before entering the academic and non-profit space, Sam worked at Google. She has a master&#8217;s degree in Modern European History from the University of Cambridge and a B.A. in History from Grinnell College. When not running CCI, Sam can usually be found biking up New England’s finest gravel mountain roads.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Karthik Dinakar</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/karthik-dinakar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Karthik Dinakar is a research affiliate at CCI. Karthik is a machine learning and clinical medicine scholar. He advises research projects at CCI. Karthik has a PhD in machine learning from MIT and is an alumnus of Carnegie Mellon University.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Karthik Dinakar is a research affiliate at CCI. Karthik is a machine learning and clinical medicine scholar. He advises research projects at CCI. Karthik has a PhD in machine learning from MIT and is an alumnus of Carnegie Mellon University.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pavish Kumar Ramani Gopal</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/pavish-kumar-ramani-gopal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2595</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pavish Kumar Ramani Gopal is a software engineer with a focus on building products that simplify complex usecases. At CCI, he works on Mathesar to help databases and data manipulation become more accessible for users of all skill levels. His past experiences include building SIEM solutions, log management products and E-commerce platforms. Apart from writing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Pavish Kumar Ramani Gopal is a software engineer with a focus on building products that simplify complex usecases. At CCI, he works on Mathesar to help databases and data manipulation become more accessible for users of all skill levels. His past experiences include building SIEM solutions, log management products and E-commerce platforms. Apart from writing code, he likes to sketch, and go on treks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brent Moran</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/brent-moran/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 12:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=person#038;p=2349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brent Moran is an automation enthusiast working on Mathesar to help automate some of the tedium out of database administration, and making databases approachable for laypeople. Previously, he was engineering data at Creative Commons, helping to gather data for an image search engine. In a past life, he was a musician working in Kansas City, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Brent Moran is an automation enthusiast working on Mathesar to help automate some of the tedium out of database administration, and making databases approachable for laypeople. Previously, he was engineering data at Creative Commons, helping to gather data for an image search engine. In a past life, he was a musician working in Kansas City, and later Denver. When he&#8217;s not at the computer, he enjoys exploring the outdoors with his dog Erdős.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dhaval Adjodah</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/dhaval-adjodah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dhaval Adjodah is a machine learning and policy researcher working on pushing the limits of modern machine learning while maximizing their social good. Dhaval&#8217;s PhD thesis was in computational social science and reinforcement learning during which he was also a member of the&#160;Harvard Berkman Assembly&#160;on Ethics and Governance in Artificial Intelligence, and a fellow at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dhaval Adjodah is a machine learning and policy researcher working on pushing the limits of modern machine learning while maximizing their social good. Dhaval&#8217;s PhD thesis was in computational social science and reinforcement learning during which he was also a member of the&nbsp;<a href="https://cyber.harvard.edu/node/100114" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harvard Berkman Assembly</a>&nbsp;on Ethics and Governance in Artificial Intelligence, and a fellow at the&nbsp;<a href="https://thecenter.mit.edu/home/fellows-the-center/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dalai Lama Center For Ethics And Transformative Values</a>.</p>



<p>Previously, Dhaval worked as a data scientist in banking and insurance, as a consultant with the Veterans Health Administration, and founder of two startup incubators. He holds a masters degree from the Technology and Policy Program from the (now) Institute for Data, Systems and Society, and a bachelors in Physics, also from MIT.</p>



<p>In addition to the day-to-day work (machine learning engineering, running live online human experiments and writing papers), Dhaval enjoys being of service to the computer science and social science communities, most recently as a member of the organizing committee of the&nbsp;<a href="https://aiforsocialgood.github.io/neurips2019/organizers.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI for Social Good</a>&nbsp;conference workshop series, and on the program committees of the&nbsp;Black in AI initiative&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://wensun.github.io/rl_theory_workshop_2020_ICML.github.io/#Program%20Committee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Theoretical Foundations of Reinforcement Learning</a>&nbsp;workshop.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rajat Vijay</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/rajat-vijay/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 06:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=person#038;p=2296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rajat Vijay is a software engineer with a major inclination towards the frontend &#38; JavaScript ecosystem. He enjoys simplifying user experiences by building accessible user interfaces. He has previously worked on Voice AI platforms &#38; large scale workflow automation tools. In his free time he enjoys traveling and exploring products that track his body vitals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Rajat Vijay is a software engineer with a major inclination towards the frontend &amp; JavaScript ecosystem. He enjoys simplifying user experiences by building accessible user interfaces. He has previously worked on Voice AI platforms &amp; large scale workflow automation tools. In his free time he enjoys traveling and exploring products that track his body vitals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ghislaine Guerin</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/ghislaine-guerin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ghislaine Guerin is a designer with a focus on experimenting and iterating with different design processes. During her twelve-year career in tech, she has worked on various products at healthcare and enterprise software startups. She enjoys sharing her ideas and experience with people and helping them think creatively. Ghislaine is currently the product designer for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ghislaine Guerin is a designer with a focus on experimenting and iterating with different design processes. During her twelve-year career in tech, she has worked on various products at healthcare and enterprise software startups. She enjoys sharing her ideas and experience with people and helping them think creatively.</p>



<p>Ghislaine is currently the product designer for the Mathesar project, which aims to help people collaborate, develop, and explore the potential of database technologies to meet the challenges of an increasingly complex world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peg Nottingham</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/peg-nottingham/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 13:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Margaret (Peg) Nottingham has been working in the online development world for over 25 years and has spent the past 15 focusing on User Interface (UI) and User Experience (UX) development and best practices.&#160; Peg has been an artist and a tech early adopter since childhood; she won her first drawing contest in kindergarten and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Margaret (Peg) Nottingham has been working in the online development world for over 25 years and has spent the past 15 focusing on User Interface (UI) and User Experience (UX) development and best practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Peg has been an artist and a tech early adopter since childhood; she won her first drawing contest in kindergarten and learned how to program on an Apple //e in second grade. Working so closely with art and computers throughout her life, Peg believes that beauty isn’t just visual, it’s functional as well; you can have great beauty without technology, but you cannot have great technology if it doesn’t function beautifully.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sean Colsen</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/sean-colsen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 12:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=person#038;p=2350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sean is an engineer passionate about open source software, user experience, data, and interesting problems. He brings a background in tech, non-profits, CRMs, and community organizing to his work on our Mathesar project. In his free time he enjoys mountain biking, and carpentry.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Sean is an engineer passionate about open source software, user experience, data, and interesting problems. He brings a background in tech, non-profits, CRMs, and community organizing to his work on our Mathesar project. In his free time he enjoys mountain biking, and carpentry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mukesh Murali</title>
		<link>https://centerofci.org/team/mukesh-murali/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ondrej Holiencin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 12:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://centerofci.org/?post_type=team#038;p=2498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mukesh is an engineer passionate about building systems that reduce complex problems into simple and elegant solutions. Previously he has worked on a platform for loyalty programmes, prior to which he was working on a workflow automation platform. He spends his free time at his farm or at the beach.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Mukesh is an engineer passionate about building systems that reduce complex problems into simple and elegant solutions. Previously he has worked on a platform for loyalty programmes, prior to which he was working on a workflow automation platform. He spends his free time at his farm or at the beach.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
